Curriculum Vitae



Michelle Falzon

Swiegi, Malta

+356 7909 9612

michelle_falzon@outlook.com

About

Hello! I am an artificial intelligence graduate from the University of Malta (2017). I am a hardworking and fast-learning individual who always strives to improve and adapt. I have worked in the iGaming industry for over three years and have recently switched over to the game development industry..

As a React Front End developer at Authentic Gaming, each new challenge required fast thinking and an analytical approach to find the optimal way to deliver our products quickly but reliably. In the fast-paced industry of iGaming, we strived to produce clean, maintainable, modular, efficient and reusable code.

Throughout my time at Raketech, I learnt to adapt quickly, think creatively and manage a team. Within a few months in the company, I was leading a small team with various skills and backgrounds. Our aim was to improve a small network of sites by making them engaging to our target audience, fast, responsive and increase their overall SEO performance.

The rest of my experience, though unrelated to my line of work, helped me understand the qualities needed to be a good leader and team player. I have also done some voluntary work which was incredibly rewarding. It was through this type of work that I learned proper time management and coping with new challenges.

In my free time I enjoy fencing, taking part in theatrical performances, working on artistic projects, reading and gardening.

I believe that teamwork, organization, having a willingness to learn and good time management are the keys to success!

Experience

03/2020 - Present

Software Developer - Dorado Games

- Working on both the frontend and backend side of games to bug fix and implement new features.
- Languages: Java, javascript, PHP, scss, VueJS, SQL

05/2020 - Present

Web Developer - Freelancing (self-employed)

 Freelancing Web Developer with Raketech as well as projects with other individuals/companies.

11/2019 - 03/2020

React Front End Developer - Authentic Gaming

- Developing the UI for live casino games
- Languages: React JS, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, Webpack, Web Sockets and Typescript.

09/2017 - 10/2019

Web Developer and Team Performance Coordinator - Raketech

- Languages: React, Vanilla Javascript with jQuery, SQL, PHP, HTML and CSS
- Developing an internal tool for simplifying the visualization of site metrics and Search Engine Optimization (SEO) health and recommending websites from which purchased links would improve the site's overall rank metrics. This involved the use of third party APIs, React libraries, messaging queues (RabbitMQ), database design and management.
- Maintaining, designing and developing new features for loan affiliation websites with a focus on SEO
- Overseeing team performance and coordinating tasks (both in-house and with freelancers)
- Managing the acquisition of affiliation links for each site
- Maintaining the overall SEO health of the sites by abiding to the guidelines set by Google
- Working with third parties to optimize products and sales
- Minor server side jobs such as creating CRON jobs and service files
- Winner of the Ownership and Teamwork Raketech Awards
- Winner of the Hackathon Award

07/2016 - 09/2016 Intern Front End Developer - Betsson Group

Bug fixing

Minor testing

Styling of new features

10/2015 - 12/2017 Attendant 1.T. Services - University of Malta

• Supervising computer labs

Troubleshooting

09/2015 - 03/2016 Junior Clerk - HLB Falzon & Falzon (Family Business)

06/2015 - 08/2015 Teen Group Leader - BELS

• Supervising foreign students ages 12 to 17 on activities.

03/2015 - 06/2015 Children's' Animator AfterGlow Events

Taking care of children between the ages of 3 and 10 years old

Dancing, Games, Balloon modelling

04/2014 - 03/2015 Children's' Animator - PartyTrap

07/2013 - 09/2013 Assistant - HLB Falzon & Falzon (Family Business)

Filing and updating archives

Education and training

2018

2018 Informal Leadership Training - StreetHR (Malta)

2018 The Web Developer Boolcamp - Colt Steele (Udemy)

HTML5

• CSS3

JavaScript

Bootstrap

SemanticUI

jQuery

NodeJS

NPM

• ExpressJS

REST

MongoDB

PassportJS

Vue JS 2 - The Complete Guide - Maximilian Schwarzmüller (Udemy)

Vue JS 2

Vue Router

Vuex

2014 - 2017	BSC 1CT (Artificial Intelligence – Honours) EQF level 6 – University of Malta
	 Programming in Java, C, C++, HTML + CSS, Javascript, PHP, SQL, PROLOG, MATLAB Web Development Signal Processing Data Structures and Algorithms Mathematics for Engineers Discrete Mathematics Databases Natural Language Processing Intelligent Agents Web Intelligence Advanced Game AI Entrepreneurship Object Oriented Programming Business Intelligence
	Machine Learning
	Content Based Image Retrieval and Categorization
2015	CS50 - Computer Science Introduction Course - Harvard University
	 C programming Web Development - HTML, CSS , PHP, Javascript
2012	Web Design Summer Course - STC
2012 - 2014	De La Salle College Sixth Form EQF level 4
	 Advanced level: Computing and Pure Mathematics

2001 - 2012 School Leaving Certificate Level 3 - St. Joseph School

• Intermediate level: English, Physics and Systems of Knowledge

EnglishMaltese

Maths

Religion

• Chemistry

• Biology

Physics

• French

Computer

Studies

Hobbies

2008 - 2017 Olympic Fencing - St. Paul Fencing Club

2012 - 2018 Drama and Theatrical Productions - DLS Productions/ KSU Students'

Fest

2017 - 2018 Historical Fencing — Malta Historical Fencing Association

2020 - Present Singing

Other Reading, Gardening, Basketball, Baking, Gaming, Art

Voluntary Work

07/2013 - 09/2013 Volunteer - Nature Trust Malta (Malta)

• Taking care of rehabilitating the injured turtles at Fort Lucjan

Taking care of children and collecting donations during the 'Kids on

the Coast' events

07/2013 - 11/2013 Child-care worker - MSSP Oratory

Taking care of young children and teaching them about the readings

in a simple manner as well as planning games for them

01/2014 - 10/2014 Deputy Mayor - Swiegi Youth Local Council

2015 - 2017 Subcommittee - ICTSA (ICT Students' Association)